Finding Aid for the Herschel Burke Gilbert Papers PASC-M.0268
UCLA Library Special Collections
Herschel Burke Gilbert papers
1946-1969
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gilbert, Herschel Burke
PASC-M.0268
206.5 Linear Feet (409 boxes)
4 Audiovisual Carriers (4 film strips)
The collection consists of manuscript scores (holographs or copies) and open reel tapes of music composed by Herschel Gilbert for television series and motion pictures, and includes some related materials such as parts, cues, lyrics sheets, and sketches.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of collection unprocessed. Material in the 2018 Addition series is unavailable for access. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of The Gilbert Family Trust of 1989-Survivor's Trust in 2004, 2007, 2011, and 2018.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9950578423606533
Biographical Note
Herschel Burke Gilbert was born in 1918 in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Following early studies on the violin, he attended Milwaukee State Teachers College, then the Juilliard School of Music, where he studied conducting with Albert Stoessel and composition with Bernard Wagenaar and Vittorio Giannini. In 1942 he came to Hollywood from New York to work as a violist and arranger for the Harry James Orchestra, during which time he also studied with composer Ernst Toch. In the mid-'40s he began orchestrating and arranging for Dmitri Tiomkin (It's a Wonderful Life) and other studio composers, then going on to compose his own music for a number of feature films in the 1940s, '50s, and '60s. He was nominated for three Academy Awards: "The Thief" (1952; score); "The Moon is Blue" (1953; title song); and "Carmen Jones" (1954; score for a musical). Additional film scores included "Mr. District Attorney" (1947), "The Jackie Robinson Story" (1950), "The Bold and the Brave" (1956), "Slaughter on Tenth Avenue" (1957), and many others. Around 1951 he started composing for television, the medium for which he is perhaps best remembered. In 1958 he joined Dick Powell's Four Star Television company later becoming the company's Executive Music Director. Of particular note from this period is his title theme and music for "The Rifleman" television series. Other series for which he composed scores or themes included "Wanted: Dead or Alive", "Johnny Ringo", "Burke's Law", "Gunsmoke", "Gilligan's Island", and "The Big Valley", among others. He became music director for CBS Television Network in 1964 and retired in 1966, forming Laurel Records, a label focusing on the music of contemporary composers. In the course of his career, he served as President of the Film Music Society, the Screen Composers Guild, and the American Society of Music Arrangers and Composers (ASMAC), and also served with the LA chapters of the National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences (NARAS) and the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences.
Scope and Content
Collection is predominantly comprised of manuscript scores (holographs or copies) of music composed by Herschel Gilbert for television series and motion pictures, including some related materials such as parts, cues, lyrics sheets, and sketches.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Projects
Series 2. Sound Recordings
Series 3. Cue Sheets
Series 4. Project Development
Series 5. Correspondence
Series 6. Associations & Organizations
Series 7. Contracts and Agreements
Series 8. Rights and Royalties
Series 9. Recording Logs and Catalogs
Series 10. Performing Rights Societies
Series 11. Four Star
Series 12. CBS
Series 13. Photographs
Series 14. Financial Papers
Series 15. Promotional Materials
Series 16. Clippings
Series 17. Blank Forms and Stationary
Series 18. Artwork
Series 19. Periodicals
Series 20. Sheet Music
Series 21. Programs
Series 22. Moving Image Materials
Series 23. Gilbert Personal Papers
Television music -- Scores.; Music -- Manuscripts.; Film composers -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Motion picture music -- Scores.
- Projects, Series 1.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged alphabetically by project title.
  - Always and Forever, Subseries 131.
    - Screenplay (Box 278)
      Scope and Contents note
      "Always and Forever" original story and screenplay by Carl Krueger (producer of Comanche)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace, Subseries 110.
    - Outline, 1971 October (Box 256)
      Outline by Alene Smith.
  - Bailout at 43,000, Subseries 111.
    - Correspondence (Box 288)
    - Cue Sheets (Box 248)
      Bailout at 43,000, Pine-Thomas-Shane Prod for United Artists, cue sheets and information
    - Sheet Music for "Who Knows" (Box 288)
      lyric by Alan Bergman and Marilyn Keith, Music by Al Glasser
    - United Artists Corp. Correspondence (Box 267)
  - The Bandit, Subseries 2.
    - [Contents Unidentified], 64 pages; 9.5 x 13 in.; manuscript orchestral parts, black ink, ozalids (Box 117)
      General note
      Production no. 540. Record no. 1963. 64 originals. Many pages have been cut.
    - A Sad Day (cue title), 2 pages; 2 guitars,bass guitar; 10.5 x 16.75 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14207. Record no. 1962. 2 originals. Episode no. 9 B.
    - Al Hombre (introduction) (cue title), 11 pages; trumpet, violin maraccas,drums, 2 guitars,bass; 10.5 x 13.25 in.; red and black pencil full score,14 staves (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14196. Record no. 1956.
    - Cantina Music (cue title), 2 pages; violin, trumpet, guitar, bass, percussion; 10.5 x 16 3/8 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14193, 4A-2. Record no. 1949. 2 originals.
    - End Title, 3 pages; cello,guitar,bassguitar,2tpts,2clarinets, voice,fl,bass; 10 3/8 x 17 in.; autograph black ink short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14185, 9C. Record no. 1943. 3 originals. Contains only a fragment of the third page.
    - Guntz Shot (cue title), 2 pages; mandolin, guitars,bassguitar,celli,bassi,clarinets; 10.5 x 16 3/8 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Only a portion of the second page is included.
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14187, 9A. Record no. 1945. 2 originals.
    - Guntz Shot (episode title), 5 pages; fl,2cl, perc, tpt, mandolin, 2 guitar, bass buitar, cellos, bass; 11 x 14 in.; pencil manuscript music,18 staves, red annotations (Box 2)
      Cue number: 14178. Record no. 419. Also composed by Joseph Mullendore. File title: Bandit.Fullscore.short score.
    - I Was Too Young (cue title), 2 pages; 2 guitars,bass guitar, voice, celli, bass; 11.25 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14209. Record no. 1952. 2 originals.
    - I Was Too Young (cue title), 2 pages; 2 guitars,bass guitar, voice, celli, bass; 11.25 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14209, 2D. Record no. 1952. 2 originals.
    - Leave Manuel (cue title), 3 pages; mandolin,guitars,celli,tpts,strings,clarinets; 10 3/8 x 16 3/8 in.; autograph black ink short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14186, 8B. Record no. 1944. 3 originals.
    - Little Drunk, A (cue title), 3 pages; 2 cl, 2 guitar, bass guitar, voice, celli, bass; 11 x 17 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14191, 3B. Record no. 1955. 3 originals.
    - Love Scene (cue title), 8 pages; 2 guitars, bass guitar, violin, celli, bass; 11 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14204. Record no. 1960. 8 originals. Episode no. 7B.
    - Manuel Decides to Kill (cue title), 1 pages; mandolin, 2 guitars, bass guitar, violin; 10.5 x 16.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14201-14202, 5C, 6B. Record no. 1957.
    - Manuel Stalking (cue title), 2 pages; guitars, celli, bass, fl, clarinets, trumpets, percussion; 10.5 x 17 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14188, 14190, 6A. Record no. 1946.
    - Manuel Stalking (cue title), 2 pages; guitars, celli, bass, fl, clarinets, trumpets, percussion; 10.5 x 17 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14188; 14190. Record no. 1946.
    - Manuel Wakes Up (cue title), 4 pages; clarinets, mandolin, 2 guitars, bass guitar, violin,celli,bass; 11 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14200, 6C. Record no. 1958. 4 originals.
    - Maria Anticipates Santiago (cue title), 2 pages; mandolin,2 guitars, bass guitar, violin, celli,bass; 11 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14203, 7A-1. Record no. 1959. 2 originals.
    - Maria Confesses (cue title), 2 guitars,bass guitar, violin, 8 celli, bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, ozalid, 14 staves (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14205, 3A. Record no. 1954. 4 originals. 2 staves cut out of each of three pages.
    - Maria Hums (episode title), 1 pages; 9.5 x 12 in; manuscript ink melody line,10 staves (Box 2)
      Cue number: 2B. Record no. 411. No composer signature. File title: Bandit.Fullscore.short score.
    - Meet Manuel (cue title), 3 pages; 2cl,mandolin,2 guitars,bassguitar, voice, celli, bass; 11.25 x 17.5 in; autograph black ink music manuscript, full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14189. Record no. 1947. 3 originals. Episode no. 2C.
    - Outside Cantino (cue title), 2 guitars,percussion,violin, trumpet; 10.5 x 17 in.; autograph black ink manuscript short score, 16 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Last page only.
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14192, 4A-1. Record no. 1948. 2 originals.
    - Santiago Leaves (cue title), 2 guitars, bass guitar, violin, celli, bass; 11 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 9 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14206. Record no. 1961. Episode no. 8A.
    - Take Money (cue title), 1 pages; mandolin, 2 guitars, bass guitar, cellos, bass; 11.25 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14208, 2E. Record no. 1953.
    - Vicente Buried (cue title), 5 pages; mandolin,2 guitars, bass guitar, voice, 8 celli, bass; 11.25 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink music manuscript full score, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue nos. 14210, 2A. Record no. 1951. 5 originals.
    - Vicente Dies (cue title), 9 pages; voice, mandolin, 2 guitars, bass guitar, celli,bass; 11 x 17.5 in.; autograph black ink full score music manuscript, 18 staves, ozalid (Box 117)
      Production no. 540. Cue no. 14194. Record no. 1950. Episode no. 1C. 9 originals.
    - Waiter at Tony's Was Asking for You, The (song), 1957; 14 pages; leadsheet; 9.5 x 12.75 in.; manuscript leadsheet;photocopies (Box 2)
      Record no. 435.
    - Waiter at Tony's Was Asking for You, The (song), 1956; 12 pages; leadsheet; 8.5 x 11;9.5 x 13 in.; black ink autograph leadsheet, 10 staves; pencil sketch;photocopy (Box 2)
      Record no. 434. File title: Theme Song.
  - Barker's Luck, Subseries 3.
    - Contracts and Agreements, 1956 (Box 269)
      "Barker's Luck" by Bret Harte, from a collection published by Houghton Mifflin copyright 1896 and 1898 to Sol Saks 1956.
  - Beyond a Reasonable Doubt, Subseries 4.
    Gilbert wrote original music for this film.
    - Agreements, Cue Sheets, Correspondence, 1956 (Box 258)
  - Big Caper, Subseries 112.
    - Correspondence (Box 288)
    - Cue Sheets (Box 248)
      The Big Caper, Pine-Thomas Prod for United Artists, cue sheets and information
    - Sheet Music for, "If You're Askin Me" (Box 288)
      music by Al Glasser, lyric Alan Bergman and Marilyn Keith
    - United Artists Corp. Correspondence (Box 267)
  - Big Valley, Subseries 5.
    - Agreement between Herschel Burke Gilbert and Four Star Television (Box 251)
    - Big Valley, open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 172)
      Tape reel: 919. Log or Cue #70081-70181X4.
    - Composer's Bills (Box 251)
      HB Gilbert to Four Star for The Big Valley
    - Full Score, fl,ob,2cl,bsn,3hn,tpt,3tbn,perc,Spanishguitar,harp,strings; 11 x 17 in.; photocopy of full score, 23 staves (Box 5)
      Main Title, End Credits #1,End Credits #2,Barkley Family Tensions;Barkley agitato,Battling Barkleys,Barkley Chase;Big Valley agitato #1, Big Valley Roundup at Fiesta (B.V. (Round up);Theme for Victoria (Major);Grab for land B.V. Tension #1.
      Production nos. 6300,63002,63003,63004,63007-63009. Cue nos. 18435-40;18843-18457;18442-4;18458-61;18464;18466-8. Record no. 511.
    - Full Score, fl,ob,2cl,bsn,3hn,tpt,3tbn,perc,Spanishguitar,harp,strings; 11 x 17 in.; photocopy of full score, 23 staves (Box 6)
    - Honey West / Big Valley, 1965 June 24; open reel audio tape, 1/2 in. (Box 197)
      Tape reel: 1336. Log or Cue # 18196 - 18218.
    - Honey West and Big Valley, 1965 June 24; open reel audio tape, 1/2 in. (Box 207)
      Tape reel: 936. Log or Cue #: 18153-18175.
    - Honey West/Big Valley, 1965 June 24; open reel audio tape, 1/2 in. (Box 193)
      Tape Reel: 1369. Log or Cue# 18177-18195.
    - Main Title, 2fl,obo,cl,bsn,4hn,tpt,3tbn,perc,harp,strings; 11 x 17 in.; photocopy of pencil ms, 23 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6301. Cues: 6301 and 6308 MainTitle;6312 Enter Heath;6313 Valley Ride;6314 The Barcleys;6315 Over that Hill;6316 Beat the train; 6317 Heath & Nick;6318 Dunking;6319 Barcleys Grave;6320 Audra;6321 Worried Ranchers;6322 Jarred advises;6323 Heath arrives;6324 Sign him on;6325 Bastard Son;6326 Heath mad; 6327 Heath's story; 6328 Heath's Mother;6329 Audra intrigued;6330 With a man;6331 Hold it;6332 Burned out;6333 Sheriffs' edict;6334 I'm sorry;6335 Victoria & Heath;6336 Birthright;6337 Battle Prelude;6338 After the Battle;6339 Harry, you're wrong;6340 Rivalry;6341 Valley Stings.
    - Main Title, 2fl,obo,cl,bsn,4hn,tpt,3tbn,perc,harp,strings; 11 x 17 in.; photocopy of pencil ms, 23 staves (Box 6)
    - The Big Valley, 1965 November 19; open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 177)
      Tape reel: 1250.
    - The Big Valley, 1965 November 19; open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 177)
      Tape reel: 1255.
    - The Big Valley, open reel audio tape, 1/4 in. (Box 184)
      Tape reel: 478.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 August 21; 4 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 5)
      Production number: 6301. Cue no. M32. Cue title: I'm Audre Barkley. Record no. 481.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 5; 1 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,timp,3hn,4vla,4cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6301. Cue no. M41. Cue title: Night Camp. Record no. 482.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 August 31; 2 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 5)
      Production no. 6301. Cue no. M63. Cue title: Audra Releases Stallion. Record no. 495.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 5; 2 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,4hn,3tbn,timp,6vla,4cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6301. Cue no. M61.Cue title: Turk Shoots Lloyd. Record no. 493.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 4 pages; 11 x 17 in.; (Box 5)
      No music, just blank pages with measure numbers and timings.
      Production no. 6301. Cue no. M56/60. Cue title: Ransom Paid. Record no. 492.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 6; 1 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,4hn,3tbns,6vla,4cell,2bass,timp; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6301. Cue no. M42. Cue title: Lloyd's Decision. Record no. 483.
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 5; 1 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,timp,3hn,4vla,4cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 6)
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 August 31; 2 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 6)
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 6; 1 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,4hn,3tbns,6vla,4cell,2bass,timp; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 6)
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 September 5; 2 pages; 2fl,3cl,basscl,4hn,3tbn,timp,6vla,4cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 6)
    - The Marauders (episode title), 1965 August 21; 4 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 6)
    - The Marauders (episode title), 4 pages; 11 x 17 in.; (Box 6)
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 16; 1 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no. 6. Cue title: Maria Play On. Record no. 502.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 19; short score; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no. 9. Cue title: Heath Reveals. Record no. 505.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 20; 2 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no. 14. Cue title: Spanish Nobleman theme. Record no. 509.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 19; 3 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no.: 10. Cue title: Maria Rejects Father. Record no. 506.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 19; 5 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no. 11. Cue title: Sad End. Record no. 507.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 18; fl,cl,3hn,3tbn,2perc,2guitar,4 cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 5)
      Production no. 6317. Cue no. 13. Cue title: Spanish Buck Board. Record no. 508.
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 20; 2 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 6)
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 18; fl,cl,3hn,3tbn,2perc,2guitar,4 cello,bass; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 6)
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 19; short score; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score, 12 staves (Box 6)
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 19; 3 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 6)
    - Winner Lose All (episode title), 1965 September 16; 1 pages; 11 x 14 in.; autograph pencil short score (Box 6)
  - The Big Wheel, Subseries 118.
    - Recording and Music Reports, 1949 (Box 258)
  - The Bold and the Brave, Subseries 6.
    - 1955-1956 (Box 258)
      Correspondence and logs.
    - Cue Sheets, 1955 (Box 252)
      R.K.O. Radio Pictures, Inc.
    - Dooley Dies (cue title), 1955 September 1; 12 pages; 2fl,2,ob,2cl,bsn,accordian,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,2perc,strings (6,6,0,8,2); 12.25 x 20.25 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 31 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 9B. Record no. 520.
    - End Title, 12 pages; 2fl,2ob,2cl,bsn,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,3perc,chorus(TB),strings(6,6,0,8,3); 13 x 20 in; manuscript full score (Box 7)
      Cue no. 10C. Manuscript pencil full score, red and blue annotations, 34 staves. File title: Bold and the brave.Full score.
    - Fiama Cries (cue title), 1955 July 24; 9 pages; fl,ob,2cl,bsn,mandolin,guitar,accordian,strings(6,6,0,6,2); 11 x 15 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 14 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 5A. Record no. 517.
    - Fiamma, 1956; 1 pages; vocal melody; 9.5 x 12.75 in.; autograph ink vocal line,10 staves, ozalid (Box 7)
      Studio: RKO. Copyright owner: Bourne, Inc. Record no. 529.
    - Fiamma, 1956 May 8; 19 pages; 8.5 x 11;9.5 x 13 in.; photocopies of various versions of theme song (Box 7)
      Record no. 531. Typed carbon lyrics;Fiamma violin part;In Monte Carlo's Church vocal leadsheet; Fiamma is her name piano vocal; 14 items, one annotated in red ballpoint.
      Song based on the love theme from "The Bold and the Brave" an RKO release;In Monte Carlo's Church, Theme from the Bold and the Brave. Studio: RKO. Copyright owner: H-G Music Co., 1955;John-Paul Music Corp, 1957.
    - First Kiss; Stay With Me;Love Scene (cue titles), 1955 July 21; 11 pages; ob,mandolin,guitar,accordian,strings (4,4,0,4,1); 11.25 x 17.5 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 7)
      Cue nos. 3A,3B,4A. Record no. 516.
    - Full Score (Box 7)
      Cue nos. 1B,3A,3A,3B,4A,5A,7A,8A,9A,9B,9C,10A,10B. Record no. 627. Photocopy of full score.
    - Full Score, 14 pages; 14 x 17 in.; (Box 7)
      Production no. 14591. Cue nos. 2B,4A. Record no. 528.
    - God Help Serrento (Cue title), 3 pages; track,mandolin,accordian; 10.5 x 12.75 in.; manuscript short score, 12 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 3C. Record no. 525.
    - God Help Serrento (cue title), 2 pages; viol,mandolin; 9.5 x 12.5 in.; manuscript pencil sketch, 10 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 3C. Record no. 526.
    - Instrumental Breakdown, 1955 August 8; 4 pages; 2fl,2ob,2cl,bsn,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,accordian,mandolin,3perc,16 singers; 11 x 14;11.5 x 14.25;13 x 19 in.; printed instrumental breakdown forms, filled in with manuscript and typing (Box 7)
      Studio: Goldwyn Studio, Standard Productions. Record no. 512.
    - Main Title, 32 pages; 2fl,2ob,2cl,bsn,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,3perc,chorus(TB),strings(6,6,0,8,3); 13 x 19.5 in.; manuscript pencil full score, red and blue annotations, 34 staves (Box 707)
      Cue no. 1A. Record no. 513. Spiral bound, paste keeping pages together drying out and pages coming apart.
    - Memories (cue title), 1955 August 30; 4 pages; fl,ob,2cl,bsn,accordian,mandolin, guitar,tpt,3tbn,perc,strings (5,5,0,6,1); 11.25 x 17.5 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 9A. Record no. 519.
    - Preacher Reforms (cue title), 1955 August 8; 6 pages; fl,ob,2cl,bsn,mandolin,accordian,tpt,tbn,guitar,perc,strings (5,5,0,6,1); 11.25 x 17.5 in.; autograph? Full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 10B. Record no. 522.
    - Recon Patrol (cue title), 6 pages; 2fl,2,ob,2cl,bsn,accordian,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,perc,strings (5,5,0,6,1); 12,5 x 20 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 31 staves (Box 7)
      Cue no. 7A. Record no. 523.
    - Recording and Music Reports, 1949 (Box 258)
    - Shoot or Else; Trapped (cue titles), 1955 July 28; 9 pages; 2fl,ob,Enghorn,2cl,bsn,accordian,2tpt,3tbn,tuba,perc,strings (6,6,0,8,3); 11.25 x 17.5 in.; manuscript full score, ozalid, 18 staves (Box 7)
      Cue nos. 8A;8B. Record no. 518.
    - Sorrento; Santa Lucia (songs), 4 pages; piano vocal; 9.5 x 13 in.; photocopy of piano vocal score (Box 7)
      Record no. 532.
    - Tank Battle (cue title), 1955 August 2; 16 pages; 2fl,2,ob,2cl,bsn,3tpt,3tbn,tuba,3perc,strings (6,6,0,8,3); 12.5 x 20 in.; manuscript ink full score, ozalid, 31 staves (Box 7)
      Cue nos. 9C-10A. Record no. 521.